Guide to the Beekman Family Papers 1720-1920's MS 51
© 2011 New-York Historical Society
- Box 4, James Beekman, Gerard Beekman, 1790's - 1841 (Box 4)
  - Last Will and Testament of Gerard Beekman in 1833, Stock and Bond Certificates, Property Inventories, Beginning of Dunkin-James Beekman Controversy, 1812-1841 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Abstract of Will of James Beekman (one later made), Inventories of Estates, Copies of Bonds, circa 1830, Correspondence (Catherine Beekman From son James W. Beekman, 1834), 1818-1834 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Rent Books, Bank Books, Business Papers Primarily of Gerard Beekman, 1815-1833 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Accounts of Gerard and James Beekman, Indentures, Agreements, 1793-1837 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Accounts, Indentures, Insurance, Reciepts (bulk James W. Beekman), 1832-1836 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Assignment of Certificate in NY Society Library from William Beekman to William Beekman, Jr., Assignment of Pews #52 in New Dutch Church and #5 in North Church, Account of Furniture in William Beekman's House, 1793 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Accounts, Receipts, Letters regarding James Beekman, Jr., Lydia Beekman, and Elizabeth Dunkin, Subscriptions, Estate Papers, 1823-36 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Box 5(A), James W. Beekman Correspondence, Circa 1790's to 1871
  See White's guide, Volume 1, pages 41-62. His description has been subsequently divided into boxes 5A and 5B. 5A consists largely of correspondence.
  - James W. Beekman, Correspondence, 1837-1871 (Box 5, Folder 1, Box 5(A))
  - James W. Beekman, Correspondence, 1837-1845 (Box 5(A), Folder 2)
  - James W. Beekman, Correspondence, 1840-1845 (Box 5(A), Folder 3)
  - James W. Beekman, Correspondence, 1840-1842 (Box 5(A), Folder 4)
  - James W. Beekman, Correspondence, 1846 (Box 5(A), Folder 5)
  - James W. Beekman, Correspondence, 1847-1848 (Box 5(A), Folder 6)
  - James W. Beekman, Correspondence, 1849 (Box 5(A), Folder 7)
  - James W. Beekman, Correspondence, 1853 (Box 5(A), Folder 8)
  - James W. Beekman, Correspondence, Compositions, and Essays, 1828-1834 (Box 5(A), Folder 9)
  - James W. Beekman, Sketches, Watercolors, Maps, Penmanship, Children's Items, Exercises of Gerard and Catherine Beekman, 1820-25, undated, 1850 (Box 5(A), Folder 10)
- Box 5(B), Diaries and School Notebooks
  - Correspondence, Accounts (bulk James W. Beekman), envelope, 1854-1860 (Box 5(B), Folder 11 (Part 1))
  - Correspondence, Accounts, Envelopes, 1777-1875 (Box 5(B), Folder 11 (Part 2))
  - Gerard Beekman, Columbia College Cards, Admissions, 1789-1792 (Box 5(B), Folder 12)
  - Diaries and Pocketbooks of James W. Beekman, Dated 1849, 1850, 1856, 1863, 1849-1863 (Box 5(B), Folder 13)
  - School Notebooks of Cornelia and Kate Beekman, 1849-1863, undated (Box 5(B), Folder 14)
  - School Notebooks of Nellie Beekman, 1863, Undated (Box 5(B), Folder 15)
  - School Notebooks, Willie Beekman and unidentified, 1842, 1860, undated (Box 5(B), Folder 16)
  - School Notebooks, no name of pupil, undated (Box 5(B), Folder 17)
- Box 6(A), James W. Beekman, Real Estate and Business Papers, 1811-1870's
  See White's guide: Vol 1 pages 63-77. His descriptions have since been divided between boxes 6(A) and 6(B), with the bulk of 6(A) holding 19th century materials, 6(B) holding 18th century materials.
  - Assessments, 1854-1860 (Box 6(A), Folder 1)
  - Report to the Board of Governors of the Society of the New York Hospital, 1866 (Box 6(A), Folder 2)
  - Notes on the founding of New York Hospital, notes on the history of medicine (bulk 19th century), 1624-1871, undated (Box 6(A), Folder 3)
  - Bills for construction, 1842-1843 (Box 6(A), Folder 4)
  - Assessments to Central Park and 51st Street, 1856-1860 (Box 6(A), Folder 5)
  - Fire insurance policies, 1865-1876 (Box 6(A), Folder 6)
  - Business Papers, Accounts relating to Property, Dutch Reformed Church, Taxes, Insurance, 1858-1873 (Box 6(A), Folder 7)
  - Deeds, Bonds, Indentures (mostly drafts), Women's Hospital, 1811-1829 (Box 6(A), Folder 8)
  - Documents pertaining to Trinity Cemetery, the Women's Hospital, and Business in Paris. Also, Correspondence and Receipts, Circa 1860-1870 (Box 6(A), Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1851-1857 (Box 6(A), Folder 10)
  - Account with William Foey (1840's), Notes on the Village of Hospitals Idea (1870's), 1840's-1870's (Box 6(A), Folder 11)
  - Receipts for Gerard Beekman's House at Broadway and Spring St, 1832 (Box 6(A), Folder 12)
- Box 6(B), James W. Beekman, Real Estate and Business Papers, 1748-1857
  - Receipts for Gerard Beekman's House at Broadway and Spring St, 1832 (Box 6(B), Folder 13)
  - Real Estate and Business Papers, Property Deeds (bulk 1795-1805), East River Bank Checkbook (1857), 1795-1857 (Box 6(B), Folder 14)
  - Real Estate and Business Papers, Deeds, Leases, 1748-1806 (Box 6(B), Folder 15)
  - Real Estate and Business Papers, Deeds, 1787-1831 (Box 6(B), Folder 16)
  - Real Estate and Business Papers, Deeds, 1803-1818 (Box 6(B), Folder 17)
  - Account Books, Bank Books, 1825-1893 (Box 6(B), Folder 18)
- Box 7(A)- Part 1, 1804-1842
  See White's Guide: pages 78-82. This box is divided into two boxes, 7(A) Parts 1-2 and 7(B). Material from 7(B) is not properly cataloged in White's guide. Overall, receipts are roughly chronological by folder but are not organized chronologically in White's guide.
  - Receipts, 1804-1805 (Box 7(A)- Part 1, Folder 1)
  - Receipts, 1811-1813 (Box 7(A)- Part 1, Folder 2)
  - Receipts, 1828-1829 (Box 7(A)- Part 1, Folder 3)
  - Receipts, Rent, Tuition, etc., 1827-1830 (Box 7(A)- Part 1, Folder 4)
  - Receipts, 1830-1831 (Box 7(A)- Part 1, Folder 5)
  - Receipts, 1831-32 (Box 7(A)- Part 1, Folder 6)
  - Receipts, 1832-1833 (Box 7(A)- Part 1, Folder 7)
  - Receipts, 1833-34 (Box 7(A)- Part 1, Folder 8)
  - Receipts, 1835-1837 (Box 7(A)- Part 1, Folder 9)
  - Receipts, 1839-1840 (Box 7(A)- Part 1, Folder 10)
  - Receipts, 1841 (Box 7(A)- Part 1, Folder 11)
  - Receipts, 1842 (Box 7(A)- Part 1, Folder 12)
- Box 7(A)- Part 2, Household Receipts for James W Beekman and Others, 1843-1865
  - Receipts, 1843-1844 (Box 7(A)- Part 2, Folder 13)
  - Receipts, 1845-46 (Box 7(A)- Part 2, Folder 14)
  - Receipts, 1847-1848 (Box 7(A)- Part 2, Folder 15)
  - Receipts, 1849-1850 (Box 7(A)- Part 2, Folder 16)
  - Receipts, 1851 (Box 7(A)- Part 2, Folder 17)
  - Receipts, 1852 (Box 7(A)- Part 2, Folder 18)
  - Receipts, 1854 (Box 7(A)- Part 2, Folder 19)
  - Receipts (Europe), 1854-1855 (Box 7(A)- Part 2, Folder 20)
  - Receipts, 1865 (Box 7(A)- Part 2, Folder 21)
- Box 7(B), Household Receipts for James W Beekman and Others, 1857-1871
  - Receipts, 1865 (Box 7(B), Folder 22)
  - Receipts, 1865-1869 (Box 7(B), Folder 23)
  - Receipts, 1870 Jan- 1870 June (Box 7(B), Folder 24)
  - Receipts, 1870 June- 1870 Dec (Box 7(B), Folder 25)
  - Receipts, 1871 (Box 7(B), Folder 26)
  - Receipts, 1857-1858 (Box 7(B), Folder 28, Folder 27)
  - Misc Letters, 1857-1858 (Box 7(B), Folder 28)
- Box 8(A), James W. Beekman, Receipts, Contracts, Correspondence, 1850-1873
  See White's guide: Pages 83-90. The content of boxes 8(A) and 8(B) is all cataloged in White's guide, though not divided into the two boxes in his notes.
  - Receipts, 1871-1872 (Box 8(A), Folder 1)
  - Receipts, 1875 (Box 8(A), Folder 2)
  - Contracts, Bonds, and Mortgages Regarding Houses Being Constructed on 51st Street, 1862-1865 (Box 8(A), Folder 3)
  - Contracts re Construction Work, 1863-1871 (Box 8(A), Folder 4)
  - Contract Records of Imports, Circa 1863-1874 (Box 8(A), Folder 5)
  - Contracts, Correspondence, Tax Assessments, Newspaper Clippings, Circa 1845-1877 (Box 8(A), Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, Contracts, Estate Income, Leases, Bulk, 1862-1877; 1845-1877 (Box 8(A), Folder 7)
  - Cancelled Checks and Drafts, 1872-1873 (Box 8(A), Folder 8)
  - James W. Beekman and Gerard Beekman, Correspondence Received from E.D. Howland, 1872-1873 (Box 8(A), Folder 9)
- Box 8(B), James W. Beekman, 1794-1908
  See also the few remaining documents concerning the Beekman/Dunscomb/Chalmers/Burr case in Box 11.
  - Cancelled Checks, Gerard Beekman, 1816-1829, 1833 (Box 8(B), Folder 10)
  - Checks of Gerard Beekman and James Beekman, 1829-1870 (Box 8(B), Folder 11)
  - James W. Beekman vs Samuel W. Dunscomb and Andrew Chalmers, Execs of Aaron M. Burr Estate, 1857-1870 (Box 8(B), Folder 12)
    Also see Box 9 folders 3, 5,6 for the Dunscomb Case.
  - James W. Beekman vs Samuel W. Dunscomb and Andrew Chalmers, Execs of Aaron M. Burr Estate, 1857-1869 (Box 8(B), Folder 13)
  - James W. Beekman vs Samuel W. Dunscomb and Andrew Chalmers, Execs of Aaron M. Burr Estate, 1858-1870 (Box 8(B), Folder 14)
  - James W. Beekman vs Samuel W. Dunscomb and Andrew Chalmers, Execs of Aaron M. Burr Estate, 1858-1867 (Box 8(B), Folder 15)
  - Deeds and Mortgages, Survey of Property, 1865-1866, 1853 (Box 8(B), Folder 16)
  - Mortgage, Miscellaneous Realty Papers, Dower, 1793-1843 (Box 8(B), Folder 17)
  - Legal Papers, Lease, Bonds, Mortgages, Deed, 1794-1840 (Box 8(B), Folder 18)
  - Receipts, Estimates, Probate Material, Indenture, 1840's - 1870's (Box 8(B), Folder 19)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Draft of Article by James W. Beekman on Family History, 1897-1908 (Box 8(B), Folder 20)
    This folder missing altogether from White's summary volumes
- Box 9, James W. Beekman, Real Estate, 1810-1880
  See White's guide: pages 92-94.
  - Leases and Indentures, 1866-1879 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Leases and Indentures, 1866-1879 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Letters of A.M. Burr to James W. Beekman (Box 9, Folder 3)
    Bulk pertaining to the Dunscomb Case. See box 8(B) folders 12-15.
  - Real Estate Papers (Leases, Mortgages, Conveyances), 1862-1873 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Real Estate Papers (Properties Sold to S.W. Dunscomb, Lexington Ave), 1868 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    Also see Box 8(B) folders 12-15, Box 9 folder 3 and 5, for the Dunscomb Case.
  - Leases and Legal Papers Relating to Dunscomb Case, 1857-1869 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    Also see box 8(B) folders 12-15 for the Dunscomb Case
  - Abstract of Title of Michael J. Newman to Premises on NW Corner of Lex and 62nd, 1810-1869 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Box 10, James W. Beekman, 1850-1853
  See White's Guide: pages 95-99.
  - James W. Beekman, Speech Delivered in Senate regarding Union College Scandal, 1852 Feb 28 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Act to Divide 19th Ward, Jones Wood Park (and supporting materials: bills, interviews, correspondence, maps, legal history), One Letter on Union College, 1853 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence to Senator James W. Beekman at Albany, 1850 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    Itemized in detail in White's guide. Organized roughly chronologically.
- Box 11, Misc Papers of James W. Beekman, 1750-1894
  See White's notes: pages 100-105. Some of these folders also contain documents from the Milledoler family as well as the Beekman/Dunscomb/Chalmers/Burr case (the bulk of which can be found in box 8(B)). Each of the folders contains a wide range of documents from legal papers to poetry to school report cards.
  - Remedies and Recipes, Extracts of Will of Harmanus Rutgers, Maps of Lots, Stock in Brunswick Turnpike, Real Estate Docs, Boudinot and Milledoler Papers, Correspondence, 1750-1808 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Letters, Baron von Hoffman Case, Medical Disability Certificate for Gereard Beekman, War of 1812, Real Estate, Death Notices for Gerard and Catherine's Children, Quotations, Milledoler Property, 1812-1828 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Letters, Recipes, Personal Notes, Correspondence, 1830-1840 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, Insurance Documentation, Gubernatorial Resolutions, 1840-1850 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Assessments, Letters, Notes on New York Hospitals, Petitions, Introductions, Club Memberships, 1850-1860 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Letters, Correspondence, Documents relating to Women's Hospital, NY Hospital, Inebriate Asylum, Century Club, Receipts, Introductions. Also, Circular of Working Women's Protective Union, 1860-1870 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Letters, Recipes for Medical Prescriptions, Notes on Adjusting a Lightning Rod. Letter in French concerning Bellerive. Legal Papers. Late 18th Century to 1894 (bulk 1870-1894), Circa 1800-1900 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Circulars, Documents Relating to Women's Hospital, School Papers, Speeches, Medical Remedies, 1850, 1867-68 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Gerard Beekman's Bills (mostly hotel) from Paris, Rome, Wiesbaden, 1864-1865 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Bank Deposits, List of Expenditures and Incomes, Construction Accounts, 1868-69 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Quotations, Poetry, Report Cards, Sermons, 1784-1830, undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - List of Jewelry, Travel Letters, Sermons, Invitations, Many Undated, Circa 1830 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Two Photographs, Maps, Will of A.W. Beekman, Property Deeds, Newspaper Clippings, Indentures, Introductions, 1821-1883 (Box 11, Folder 13)
- Box 12, Genealogy and Property, 1719-1923
  See White's guide: pages 105-109.
  - Petition in Chancery 1836 re Division of Property Among Heirs of William Beekman, Other Papers re Petition including Commissioner's Reports (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Genealogy, Family History, 5 Mile Stone Farm, Property Deeds, Indentures, 1767-1799, 1923 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Genealogy, Family History, 5 Mile Stone Farm, Correspondence, 1832, undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Genealogy, 5 Mile Stone Farm, Newspaper Clippings, 1760-1839, 1903-1916 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Genealogy (particularly European Beekmans), 5 Mile Stone Farm, Includes Some Photostat Copies, 1719, Undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Indentures, 1751-1780 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Agreements, Deed of Partition, Bill of Sale (Box 12, Folder 7)
    Bill of Sale's description missing from White's Guide
  - Leaves of Record of Family of William Beekman (in Dutch with translation) (Box 12, Folder 8)
    Leaves of Record missing from White's guide.
- Box 13(A), James Beekman, 1750-1759
  See White's guide: pages 110-116. White's description is of one box but later was divided into two (13(A-B)). Items are arranged largely chronologically but not corresponding to White's guide directly.
  - James Beekman, Accounts and Correspondence, 1750-1753 (Box 13(A), Folder 1)
  - James Beekman, Accounts and Correspondence, 1754-1755 (Box 13(A), Folder 2)
  - James Beekman, Accounts and Correspondence, 1756 (Box 13(A), Folder 3)
  - James Beekman, Accounts and Correspondence, 1757 (Box 13(A), Folder 4)
  - James Beekman, Accounts and Correspondence, 1757 (Box 13(A), Folder 5)
  - James Beekman, Accounts and Correspondence, 1758 (Box 13(A), Folder 6)
  - James Beekman, Accounts and Correspondence, 1758-59 (Box 13(A), Folder 7)
- Box 13(B), James Beekman, 1759-1760
  Folders 8-9 in this box are describes by White under folder #4 in the guide. Similarly, folder 10 of this box is described as folder #5 in White's guide.
  - James Beekman, Accounts and Correspondence, 1759 (Box 13(B), Folder 8)
  - James Beekman, Accounts and Correspondence, 1759 (Box 13(B), Folder 9)
  - James Beekman, Accounts and Correspondence, 1760 (Box 13(B), Folder 10)
- Box 14(A), James Beekman, 1760-1766
  For 14(A-B) see White's guide: pages 117-125. Folders have been reorganized and no longer correspond to the folders detailed in White's guide but many are present.
  - James Beekman, European Accounts and Correspondence, Pertaining Largely to London Firm Pomeroys and Hodgkin, 1760 (Box 14(A), Folder 1)
  - James Beekman, European Accounts and Correspondence, Pertaining Largely to London Firm Pomeroys and Hodgkin, 1761 (Box 14(A), Folder 2)
  - James Beekman, European Accounts and Correspondence, Pertaining Largely to London Firm Pomeroys and Hodgkin, 1762 (Box 14(A), Folder 3)
  - James Beekman, European Accounts and Correspondence, Pertaining Largely to London Firm Pomeroys and Hodgkin, 1763 (Box 14(A), Folder 4)
  - James Beekman, European Accounts and Correspondence, Pertaining Largely to London Firm Pomeroys and Hodgkin, 1764 (Box 14(A), Folder 5)
  - James Beekman, European Accounts and Correspondence, Pertaining Largely to London Firm Pomeroys and Hodgkin, 1764 (Box 14(A), Folder 6)
  - James Beekman, European Accounts and Correspondence, Pertaining Largely to London Firm Pomeroys and Hodgkin, 1765 (Box 14(A), Folder 7)
  - James Beekman, European Accounts and Correspondence, Pertaining Largely to London Firm Pomeroys and Hodgkin, 1766 (Box 14(A), Folder 8)
- Box 14(B), James Beekman, 1767-1775, undated
  - James Beekman, Accounts and Correspondence, 1767 (Box 14(B), Folder 9)
  - James Beekman, Accounts and Correspondence, 1768 (Box 14(B), Folder 10)
  - James Beekman, Accounts and Correspondence, 1769 (Box 14(B), Folder 11)
  - James Beekman, Accounts and Correspondence, 1770 (Box 14(B), Folder 12)
  - James Beekman, Accounts and Correspondence, 1771 (Box 14(B), Folder 13)
  - James Beekman, Accounts and Correspondence, 1772 (Box 14(B), Folder 14)
  - James Beekman, Accounts and Correspondence, 1773 (Box 14(B), Folder 15)
  - James Beekman, Accounts and Correspondence, 1774 (Box 14(B), Folder 16)
  - James Beekman, Accounts and Correspondence, 1775 (Box 14(B), Folder 17)
  - James Beekman, Undated Papers (Box 14(B), Folder 18)
- Box 15(A), James Beekman, Business Papers, 1760-1785
  For 15(A-B) see White's guide: pages 126-141. Very detailed notes but, because of post-White reorganization, does not always line up with folders.
  - James Beekman, European Business Correspondence EMPTY, 1776-1781 (Box 15(A), Folder 1)
  - James Beekman, European Business Correspondence, 1782 (Box 15(A), Folder 2)
  - James Beekman, European Business Correspondence, 1783 (Box 15(A), Folder 3)
  - James Beekman, European Business Correspondence, 1784 (Box 15(A), Folder 4)
  - James Beekman, European Business Correspondence, 1785 (Box 15(A), Folder 5)
  - James Beekman, Local Correspondence, Accounts, Indentures, 1760-1762 (Box 15(A), Folder 6)
  - James Beekman, Local Correspondence, Accounts, Indentures, 1763-1765 (Box 15(A), Folder 7)
  - James Beekman, Local Correspondence, Accounts, Indentures, 1766-1769 (Box 15(A), Folder 8)
  - James Beekman, Local Correspondence, Accounts, Indentures, 1770 (Box 15(A), Folder 9)
  - James Beekman, Local Correspondence, Accounts, Indentures, 1771 (Box 15(A), Folder 10)
  - James Beekman, Local Correspondence, Accounts, Indentures, 1772 (Box 15(A), Folder 11)
- Box 15(B), James Beekman, Business Papers, 1773-1814
  - James Beekman, Local Invoices, Receipts, Agreements, Lists of Bonds, Lake Champlain Property, 1773 (Box 15(B), Folder 12)
  - James Beekman, Local Invoices, Accounts, Receipts, Legal Papers, 1774-1776 (Box 15(B), Folder 13)
  - James Beekman, Local Correspondence, Invoices, Accounts, Receipts, Extract of Will of Gerard W. Beekman, 1777-1781 (Box 15(B), Folder 14)
  - James Beekman, Local Correspondence (Two from Mary Beekman), 1782 (Box 15(B), Folder 15)
  - James Beekman, Local Accounts, Receipts, 1783 (Box 15(B), Folder 16)
  - James Beekman, Local Accounts, Receipts, Lake Champlain Property, 1784 (Box 15(B), Folder 17)
  - James Beekman, Local Correspondence, Accounts, Receipts, 1785 (Box 15(A), Folder 18)
  - James Beekman, Local Correspondence, Accounts, Receipts, 1787 (Box 15(B), Folder 19)
  - James Beekman, Local Accounts, Receipts, 1792 (Box 15(B), Folder 20)
  - James Beekman, Local Maps and Property Documents, Correspondence, Accounts, Receipts, 1796-1799 (Box 15(B), Folder 21)
  - James Beekman, Local Correspondence and Survey of Property, 1804-1814 (Box 15(B), Folder 22)
  - James Beekman, Local Correspondence, Business Papers, French Account and Letters (in French), 1791-1799 (Box 15(B), Folder 23)
- Box 16(A), William Beekman Jr. (Beekmantown), 1735-1789
  For boxes 16(A-B) see White's guide: pages 232-251. Organized largely chronologically in White's notes but split into two boxes after the fact. Much of the content pertains to Beekmantown.
  - William Beekman Jr., Accounts, Correspondence, Wills and Receipts belonging to Robert Gregg (bulk), 1746-1759 (Box 16(A), Folder 1)
  - William Beekman Jr., Accounts, Correspondence, Probate Materials, 1760-1769 (Box 16(A), Folder 2)
  - William Beekman Jr., Accounts, Correspondence, Estate Inventories, Bonds, Wawayanda Property, 1770-1771 (Box 16(A), Folder 3)
  - William Beekman Jr. and Abraham Beekman, Accounts, Correspondence, Estate Division, Household Receipts, 1772-1773 (Box 16(A), Folder 4)
  - William Beekman Jr., Accounts, Correspondence, Bonds, 1774-1775 (Box 16(A), Folder 5)
  - William Beekman Jr., Accounts, Correspondence, Bound Account book with Gerard Beekman, 1776-1784 (Box 16(A), Folder 6)
  - William Beekman Jr., Accounts, Correspondence, Survey of Beekmantown, Bulk, 1785-1786; 1735-1786 (Box 16(A), Folder 7)
  - William Beekman Jr. and Abraham Beekman, Accounts, Correspondence, Document Pertaining to Education of Slave, 1787-1788 (Box 16(A), Folder 8)
  - William Beekman Jr., Accounts, Correspondence, Bill of Sale for Slave (made by Elizabeth Rutgers), 1789 (Box 16(A), Folder 9)
- Box 16(B), William Beekman Jr. (Beekmantown), 1790-1828
  - William Beekman Jr., Accounts, Correspondence, Receipts, NH Border, Egbert Benson Correspondence, 1790 (Box 16(B), Folder 10)
  - William Beekman Jr., Accounts, Correspondence, Receipts, Property, 1791-1792 (Box 16(B), Folder 11)
  - William Beekman Jr., Accounts, Correspondence, Receipts, Aaron Burr Letter, Beekmantown, 1793-1794 (Box 16(B), Folder 12)
  - William Beekman Jr., Accounts, Correspondence, Receipts, Rental Agreements, Elizabeth Rutgers Rent Execution and Related Documents, 1795 (Box 16(B), Folder 13)
  - William Beekman Jr., Accounts, Correspondence, Estate, Receipts, Dividends of William Beekman Estate, Chancery Court, Catherine Rawling and Sarah Keteltas Inheritance, 1796-1798 (Box 16(B), Folder 14)
  - William Beekman Jr., Accounts, Correspondence, Estate Papers, Receipts, Dividends of William Beekman Estate, Sarah Fish Accounts, 1799 (Box 16(B), Folder 15)
  - William Beekman Jr., Accounts, Correspondence, Receipts, City Maintenance, William Beekman Jr Death and Related Documents, Circa 1800's (Box 16(B), Folder 16)
  - Receipts, Rent, 1800-1828 (Box 16(B), Folder 17)
- Box 17(A), William Beekman, 1695-1779
  See White's guide, Volume 1, pages 176-201.
  - William Beekman, Gerard Beekman, Accounts, Indentures, Sailing Materials, Bonds, Many Materials Pertaining to Insolvency, 1695-1745 (Box 17(A), Folder 1)
  - William Beekman and Seymour Family, Accounts and Correspondence Pertaining Largely to Business in Jamaica, 1750-1759 (Box 17(A), Folder 2)
    File Plan note
    For related materials, see Box 31(A), Folder 3, and Box 16, Folder 7.
  - William Beekman, Accounts, Receipts, Bills of Exchange, Including Information on the Schooners "William" and "Friendship", 1760-1765 (Box 17(A), Folder 3)
  - William Beekman, Accounts, Receipts, 1766-1767 (Box 17(A), Folder 4)
  - William Beekman, Accounts, Receipts, Bonds, 1768-1769 (Box 17(A), Folder 5)
  - William Beekman, Accounts, Receipts, Estate Inventory, Rents, 1770-1771 (Box 17(A), Folder 6)
  - William Beekman, Accounts, Receipts, Including Joint Bond List of Magdalen, Catherine, and Mary Beekman, 1772-1773 (Box 17(A), Folder 7)
  - William Beekman, Accounts, Receipts, Correspondence, Indentures, 1774-1776 (Box 17(A), Folder 8)
  - William Beekman, Accounts, Receipts, 1777-1778 (Box 17(A), Folder 9)
  - William Beekman, Accounts, Receipts, 1779 (Box 17(A), Folder 10)
- Box 17(B), William Beekman, 1780-1783
  - William Beekman, Accounts, Circa 1780 (Box 17(B), Folder 11)
  - William Beekman and Family, Accounts, Tax Receipts, 1781 (Box 17(B), Folder 12)
    Many accounts pertain to Mary, Catherine, and Magdelaine Beekman.
  - William Beekman, Accounts, Receipts, Hampden Hall, 1782 (Box 17(B), Folder 13)
    For more on Hampden Hall, see Box 18, Folder 2.
  - William Beekman and Family, Correspondence, Accounts, Magdalaine and Catherine and Mary Beekman Rental Execution, 1783 (Box 17(B), Folder 14)